### **Stephen Thompson**

#### **Professional Summary:**

I am an Information Technology professional with over 20 years of practical experience in systems administration, systems security and consulting. I have experience in network troubleshooting, firewalls, routers and remote network management and some coding. Maintain and troubleshoot Windows, Linux and iSeries servers. Negotiate contracts with vendors and contractors. Experience in creating and maintaining company IT policies and procedures. I have superior troubleshooting and problem solving skills. I can grasp new technology and concepts quickly. I am able to work independently in fast-paced high pressure environments.

#### **Professional Experience:**

October 2010 - Present

TransAm Trucking, Inc.
IT Support Engineer

Maintain EDI mapping and programming transaction sets 204, 990, 214, 210 and 820. Use SQL coding for various reports or projects. Provide regular and on-call support and maintenance in a 24x7x365 production environment for iSeries servers, Windows servers and PCs. Maintain and troubleshoot network switches, firewalls and routers. Maintain security system servers and cameras. Maintain and troubleshoot tractor routing calculations using MySQL for fuel solutions. Mange iTERA data replication to ensure high availability for disaster recovery site. Support CADENCE factoring software. Support and troubleshoot tractor diagnostic software packages: CAT ET, DAVIE, ServiceRanger, Diagnostic Link and EDiTH

### Technologies supported and used:

- iSeries, iOS 5 and AS/400
- iTERA HA
- SEQUEL ViewPoint
- SQL Server 2008, 2012
- MySQL
- X12: 204, 990, 214, 210, 820
- McLeod LoadMaster EDI
- Cleo LexiCom
- AS2
- Windows Servers 2003, 2008, 2012
- IDSC Fuel and Routing software
- PC\*Miler
- CADENCE for Factoring
- R:COM
- WatchGuard Firewalls and WiFi
- Avaya Switches
- Mitel Phone system
- VMware
- Honeywell security system

October 2008 - October 2010

CODEMED, Inc.
Systems Administrator

Manage day-to-day network operations of a Health Information Management services company. Responsibilities include systems administration, create and maintain company IT policies and procedures, maintain information and systems security. Troubleshoot technical problems for end users. Manage Windows Server 2003 and 2008. Manage Red Hat 5 and SUSE 11 Linux servers. Make decisions and/or recommendations and negotiated with vendors and contractors on the procurement of equipment and services.

#### Notable accomplishments and contributions:

- Migrated company information systems from a simple peer-to-peer network to a more secure client/server based network located in a data center.
- Establish and implemented IT policies and procedures.
- Implemented new information security measures and policies to reduce and eliminate data leakage.
- Supervise the projects of contracting programmers hired for special projects.

#### Technical Skills and Technologies used:

- Windows Server 2003 and 2008 Administration
- Exchange Server 2007
- LDAP, AD or Active Directory
- SUSE Linux Enterprise 11 Administration
- Red Hat Enterprise Linux 5 Administration
- SonicWALL firewall appliances
- Symantec Endpoint Protection
- MS SQL Server 2005 and 2008

#### **July 2002 – October 2008**

# **Entrust Technology Enterprises, Inc. Network Systems Consultant / Owner**

I provided computer networking services to businesses. Established and maintained vendor relationships. Negotiated contracts and established new clientele relationships. I worked with clientele's in-house IT staff. Serviced clientele in various industries including: Medical, Law, Real Estate, Entertainment, Professional Sports, Manufacturing, Security, Finance and Education.

#### **Technical duties and expertise include:**

- Network assessment and planning
- Windows Server Administration
- Phone support and troubleshooting
- Routers

#### 

Assisted Career Center staff and help troubleshoot problems with computer hardware and programs. Assisted and train students on computer programs. Performed data entry to maintain and update department information on AS/400 and domino servers.

- Design and implemented database solutions using SQL and Microsoft Access for statistical analysis and reports on department surveys.
- Develop and maintained department intranet and Internet web pages.
- Provide technical support to employers for Career Center job posting web site.
- Liaison between Career Center and IT department.
- Conducted computer-training seminars and produced training manuals on Microsoft Office,
   Domino Intranet services, and SpyVision CS.

Apr. 1998 – May 2000 <u>American Guidance Service, Inc.</u>

**Systems Support** 

Input and maintained account information. Assisted, trained, and helped sales representative troubleshoot problems with computer hardware and programs. Performed computer upgrades and installed software and hardware.

 Developed and maintained solutions to help sales representative better manage day-to-day business operations using information technology.

# Sep. 1997 – Nov. 1999 <u>Virginia Road Charter School (LAUSD)</u> Computer Lab Technician/Network Systems Administrator

Managed daily operations of main computer lab. Performed hardware and software installations and upgrades, maintained computer systems throughout the campus. Assisted in troubleshooting computer and software problems.

- Taught computer classes for grades 2 5
- Managed campus wide switched ATM network using XYLAN technology.
- Implemented and maintained Mac OS computer Lab managed with AppleShare IP and Network Assistant.
- Developed and maintained school web site.
- Performed computer in-service training for teachers and visiting teachers.

July 1995 – Nov. 1997

### International Realty & Investments Computer Technician

Performed hardware and software installations and upgrades. Maintained computer equipment, Troubleshoot computer and software problems. Train staff on different computer programs.

Setup and maintained real estate management software.

**Education:** 

**DeVry University** 

Major: Computer Information Systems

California State University, Northridge Major: Management Information Systems

Westchester High School, Los Angeles, CA